San Diego, CA

410.980.9672 (cell) bheussler@gmail.com

# Summary

I am a software engineer that has been building Java applications professionally for seven years. Currently, I work for SwingAI. My most recent project is Swing Index, an on-demand mobile golf app. I also support LifeJourney, building web applications used by hundreds of students on a daily basis. Java is my most proficient language, though I also work with Javascript on the front end using AngularJS and have used Node.js for a few side projects, as well as WordPress.

# Relevant Experience

Swing Index

LifeJourney / Swing AI

2018 - Present

- Software Engineer
  - Worked on a small team of 5 to build the application from the ground up
  - Developed entities and business logic using Spring Framework and Hibernate
  - Provided backend services to iOS and Android applications via RESTful web services
  - Responsible for building the instructor scoring dashboard using AngularJS
  - Implemented an asynchronous messaging system using Apache Kafka
  - Worked closely with a designer to develop and maintain dozens of marketing websites

LifeJourney.us

LifeJourney / Swing AI

Software Engineer 2014 - Present

- Built and maintained web application in Java using Spring and Hibernate, capable of handling thousands of concurrent users by means of NGINX load balancing and multiple Tomcat servers
- Developed and maintained frontend in Javascript (Angular)
- Maintained 80% unit test coverage using JUnit and Jasmine on the back and front ends respectively,
  as well built integration tests using Geb and REST Assured
- Wrote migration scripts in Groovy that managed the migration of multiple versions of the application to satisfy multiple clients concurrently
- Built deployment scripts in Ruby using Capistrano to manage the deployment of the application to multiple environments

### MatOnto Materials Science Framework

iNovex Information Systems

Software Developer

2012-2014

- Developed RESTful web services using Groovy on Grails that orchestrated CKAN data publishing
- Built ontologies serialized in RDF to enable federated SPARQL queries across multiple data sources
- Designed Accumulo powered Graph Data store to handle high volume integrated data

#### Education

#### Connecticut College

New London, CT

B.A. Major Computer Science, Minor Economics (GPA 3.28)

2008 - 2012

 Relevant Courses: Computational Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence, Networks, Algorithms, Data Structures, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Software Engineering Methodologies

### Skills

Languages: Java (Proficient), Javascript (Proficient), Groovy (Proficient), Node.js (Competent), Ruby (Competent), HTML/CSS (Proficient), Sass (Proficient), SQL (Competent)

Frameworks & Libraries: Spring (Proficient), Hibernate (Proficient), AngularJS (Proficient), Bootstrap (Proficient), Gulp (Proficient), Webpack (Proficient)

Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Volunteer: Open Source Contributor for Twitter Bootstrap; Designer and Developer of https://usa505.org